We all know about the benefits of a healthy diet.
我们都知道健康饮食的好处。"
'We are what we eat', so some say.
吃什么像什么"，有些人这么说。
But sometimes our busy lives mean our healthy intentions slip, and we end up eating the wrong things.
但有时忙碌的生活意味着我们的健康意图会溜走，我们最终吃了不该吃的东西。
Messaging telling us to eat our 'five-a-day' encourages us to maintain a balanced diet – but is it accurate?
信息告诉我们要每天吃"五份蔬果"，鼓励我们保持均衡饮食——但这准确吗？
If you're not sure what your 'five-a-day' is, it's a campaign based on advice from the World Health Organization which recommends eating a minimum of 400g of fruit and vegetables a day.
如果你不确定什么是"每日五份蔬果"，这是一项基于世界卫生组织建议的饮食运动，该运动建议每天至少摄入400克水果和蔬菜。
That should lower the risk of serious health problems, such as heart disease, stroke and some types of cancer.
这样做能降低患严重健康问题的风险，如心脏病、中风和某些类型的癌症。
Variety is important because different fruits and vegetables contain different combinations of fibre, vitamins, minerals and other nutrients.
多样性很重要，因为不同的水果和蔬菜含有不同组合的纤维、维生素、矿物质和其他营养素。
Eating five pieces of fruit and veg is something to aim for.
争取每天吃五份水果和蔬菜。
An analysis of 16 worldwide studies suggested that for every portion of fruit and vegetables consumed, there was a lower risk of premature death.
对16项全球研究的分析表明，每摄入一份水果和蔬菜，过早死亡的风险就会降低。
And in the UK, previous research by the University of Oxford found around 33,000 lives a year could be saved if everyone in the UK followed dietary guidelines.
在英国，牛津大学之前的研究发现，如果英国每个人都遵循饮食指导方针，每年大约可以挽救33,000人的生命。
Dr Peter Scarborough told the BBC: "According to our model, the biggest impact would be eating more fruit and veg.
彼得·斯卡伯勒博士告诉BBC："根据我们的模型，最大的影响将是多吃水果和蔬菜。
But this doesn't mean you should just stop at five – the more the better."
但这并不意味着你只吃五份就够了——越多越好。"
However, there are some doubts about the 'five-a-day' message.
然而，有人质疑"每日五份蔬果"的这一信息。
Some fruits and vegetables are better than others.
有些水果和蔬菜比其他的更好。
And counting orange juice, for example, as one of your portions isn't so beneficial because it contains sugar.
例如，把橙汁算作你的一份蔬果并不是那么有益，因为它含有糖。
Also, eating more vegetables than fruit tends to be better because they're richer in nutrients.
而且，多吃蔬菜而不是水果往往更好，因为它们富含营养素。
Some doctors also say the message is too ambitious, and a 'two-a-day' message might be a more realistic starting point.
一些医生还说，这条信息过于雄心勃勃，"每日两份"可能是一个更现实的起点。
There have been calls to up the quota to seven-a-day, but research reported in The British Medical Journal found after five portions a day, there was no further impact.
一直有人呼吁将定额提高到每日七份，但发表在《英国医学杂志》上的研究发现，每天五份之后，就没有更好的效果了。
But whatever fruit and vegetables you consume, every piece can help reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease and cancer.
但无论你摄入什么水果和蔬菜，每一份都有助于降低心血管疾病和癌症的风险。
As the old saying goes: 'an apple a day keeps the doctor away'.
正如老话所说："一天一苹果，医生远离我。"